Zachary Svoboda

Software Engineer

630.589.7370 cczac1@gmail.com

Skills

Mission-motivated developer focused on end-user experience through the high impact areas of performance, accessibility and reliability.

Uses a cross-disciplinary understanding of development and design in web, applications and games to provide a highly-interactive approach to traditionally static spaces.

Frontend Web Development — Modern HTML, CSS, JS & Typescript

Application Development — C# & C++

Web Performance Optimization — Rendering and Loading Best Practices, Web Workers, PWA, JAMstack

Game Development — Unity, Flash

UX and Game Design — Principles of user interaction, MDA modeling, Accessibility

Experience

The Orvis Company, Inc. / Frontend Web Developer

February 2018 - Present, Sunderland VT

Developed responsive ecommerce front-end - Angular, RxJS, NgRX, AEM Introduced automated testing and TDD practices - Jasmine, Cypress (Unit, E2E)

Responsible for implementing user testing, personalization and recommendations - Adobe Target (Machine learning)

Self-Employed Contractor / Software Engineer, UX Designer

April 2017 - Present

Designed and Architected a music & sound licensing workflow, Vue.JS

Automated data analysis in .NET 4 for inventory software

Built ecommerce and landing pages for local small businesses, Wordpress, Gridsome

Open Source Contributor / Maintainer, Code and Docs Author

2018 - Present

Maintainer of Gridsome, Vue-based static site generator for JAMstacks

Contributions to Angular, ESLint, Gridsome, Amethyst

Open-sourced personal and professional projects

Education

Champlain College / B.S. Game Design & Development

August 2012 - May 2016, Burlington VT

Curriculum pairing theory-based courses with application through group work in 3, 6, and 12 month long projects

Awards